<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-02T14:33:40+01:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Human Boring</title><subtitle>Thoughts from a boring person</subtitle><author><name>Benjamin Hamblin-Pyke</name><email>me@humanboring.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">The Lighthouse</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2020/02/16/the-lighthouse.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Lighthouse" /><published>2020-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2020/02/16/the-lighthouse</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2020/02/16/the-lighthouse.html">&lt;p&gt;‘The lighthouse’ (2019) is the latest film by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/name/nm3211470/&quot;&gt;Robert Eggers&lt;/a&gt;, who previously directed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt4263482/?ref_=nm_flmg_dr_3&quot;&gt;The Witch&lt;/a&gt;, one of my favourite films of the last few years. In ‘The Lighthouse’ we follow Ephraim Winslow (Robert Patterson), a trainee wickie for a lighthouse on an island off the New England coast run by Thomas Wake (Willem Dafoe). With the isolated setting, paranoia soon starts to creep in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to get too much more into the plot, but it’s safe to say that this is one of my favourite films of the last decade. The black and white film, as well as the unusual 1.19:1 aspect ratio helps make this feel like a film from the 19th-centure, adding to the atmosphere. Both Patterson and Dafoe put in excellent perfomances, which is important when there aren’t realy any supporting cast. This film  has me excited to see Patterson’s take as the Batman, having proved his range and firmly established himself as a serious actor outside of the Twilight franchise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like psychological horror like ‘The Witch’ or ‘The Shining’, this is definitely a film to check out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Hamblin-Pyke</name><email>me@humanboring.net</email></author><summary type="html">‘The lighthouse’ (2019) is the latest film by Robert Eggers, who previously directed The Witch, one of my favourite films of the last few years. In ‘The Lighthouse’ we follow Ephraim Winslow (Robert Patterson), a trainee wickie for a lighthouse on an island off the New England coast run by Thomas Wake (Willem Dafoe). With the isolated setting, paranoia soon starts to creep in.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hairspray (2007)</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2020/02/04/hairspray.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hairspray (2007)" /><published>2020-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2020/02/04/hairspray</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2020/02/04/hairspray.html">&lt;p&gt;I watched Hairspray, the 2007 adaptation of the broadway stage musical adaptation of the 1988 comedy. It’s cheesy, but a very fun film that feels like it’s from another age (especially with the 1960s setting). It’s pretty strange to have Travolta in drag in one of the leading roles given his well-documented &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.today.com/popculture/travolta-says-hairspray-isnt-gay-film-wbna19512551&quot;&gt;views on homosexuality&lt;/a&gt;, but the film as a whole still&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;★★★☆☆&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Hamblin-Pyke</name><email>me@humanboring.net</email></author><summary type="html">I watched Hairspray, the 2007 adaptation of the broadway stage musical adaptation of the 1988 comedy. It’s cheesy, but a very fun film that feels like it’s from another age (especially with the 1960s setting). It’s pretty strange to have Travolta in drag in one of the leading roles given his well-documented views on homosexuality, but the film as a whole still</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Us (2019)</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/03/23/us.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Us (2019)" /><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2019/03/23/us</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/03/23/us.html">&lt;p&gt;‘Us’ is the second film by director Jordan Peele, following on from the hugely successful ‘Get Out’. This horror film focusses on a family on holiday in Santa Cruz. When the mother (Adelaide, played by Lupita Nyong’o) was a child, she had visited this beach. After wondering off on her own, she entered a hall of mirrors and met a girl who looked exactly like her, an even that scarred her. While the family is staying in the same area in the present day, Adelaide and her family are terrorised by people that look exactly like them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved this film; the acting from the main cast, the lighting and camera work, and the soundtrack were all very strong. The story all made sense as you watch it but left me and my partner discussing what exactly was going in and why things happened as they did for hours after watching it. It reminded me of ‘The Shining’ in some ways, perhaps deliberately. There was use of Native American imagery throughout, and one character limping while carrying a weapon was reminiscent to Jack Torrence at the end of ‘The Shining’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Us’ is a film I want to watch again to attempt to answer some of the questions it left me, and to look at certain scenes with the knowledge I have now. It’s definitely worth watching if you like horror films.
★★★★☆&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Hamblin-Pyke</name><email>me@humanboring.net</email></author><summary type="html">‘Us’ is the second film by director Jordan Peele, following on from the hugely successful ‘Get Out’. This horror film focusses on a family on holiday in Santa Cruz. When the mother (Adelaide, played by Lupita Nyong’o) was a child, she had visited this beach. After wondering off on her own, she entered a hall of mirrors and met a girl who looked exactly like her, an even that scarred her. While the family is staying in the same area in the present day, Adelaide and her family are terrorised by people that look exactly like them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spider-Man: Into the Spider-Verse (2018)</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/03/11/spider-man-enter-the-spiderverse.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spider-Man: Into the Spider-Verse (2018)" /><published>2019-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2019/03/11/spider-man-enter-the-spiderverse</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/03/11/spider-man-enter-the-spiderverse.html">&lt;p&gt;This film was without a doubt my favourite super-hero film of 2018. Firstly the animation is spectacular - if you haven’t already go an watch the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tg52up16eq0&quot;&gt;trailer&lt;/a&gt; and see for yourself how spectacular this film is. The only recent film with a style rivalling Spider-Verse was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1856101/&quot;&gt;Blade-Runner: 2049&lt;/a&gt; (my favourite film of 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film follows Miles Morales, a young black and latino teen living in Brooklyn who gets bitten by a radioactive spider, granting him all the powers of Spider-Man. He stubles across a supercollider that is threatening Brooklyn with distruction while also bringing other Spider-people into Miles’s universe. The casting of Jake Johnson as Peter Parker helps bring what is probably my favourite big-screen version of Parker to life. Johnson’s Spider-Man is an older, well-established hero, but has become slightly jaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spider-Verse is one of the best superhero films in years, reminding me of the early Sam Rami films in their optimism and presentation Spider-Man of a true hero for people to look up to.
★★★★☆&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Hamblin-Pyke</name><email>me@humanboring.net</email></author><summary type="html">This film was without a doubt my favourite super-hero film of 2018. Firstly the animation is spectacular - if you haven’t already go an watch the trailer and see for yourself how spectacular this film is. The only recent film with a style rivalling Spider-Verse was Blade-Runner: 2049 (my favourite film of 2017).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unfriended: Dark Web (2018)</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/02/22/unfriended-dark-web.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unfriended: Dark Web (2018)" /><published>2019-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2019/02/22/unfriended-dark-web</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/02/22/unfriended-dark-web.html">&lt;p&gt;This was not a good film. Unfriended: Dark Web is the sequel to the 2014 film &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt3713166/&quot;&gt;Unfriended&lt;/a&gt;. It shares the horror ‘gimmick’ of the whole film taking place inside a computer screen. The characters in our film are on a Skype call together, with our protagonist Mathias having stollen a laptop from a lost-and-found box. However, it turns out this computer belonged to a hacker, meaning our protagonists have become tangled in a larger game. Unlike the first film, there is almost no supernatural element to ‘Dark Web’, with the exception of the almost god-like hacking ability of the shadowy group terrorising the friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While very cheesy, this film was enjoyable throughout, though I watched it while drinking a beer with some friends so I’m not sure how fun it would be to watch alone. I would recommend this if you’re looking for a dump horror film to laugh at, but not so much if you actually want to be scared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;★★★☆☆&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Hamblin-Pyke</name><email>me@humanboring.net</email></author><summary type="html">This was not a good film. Unfriended: Dark Web is the sequel to the 2014 film Unfriended. It shares the horror ‘gimmick’ of the whole film taking place inside a computer screen. The characters in our film are on a Skype call together, with our protagonist Mathias having stollen a laptop from a lost-and-found box. However, it turns out this computer belonged to a hacker, meaning our protagonists have become tangled in a larger game. Unlike the first film, there is almost no supernatural element to ‘Dark Web’, with the exception of the almost god-like hacking ability of the shadowy group terrorising the friends.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Incredibles 2 (2018)</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/02/12/Incredibles-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Incredibles 2 (2018)" /><published>2019-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2019/02/12/Incredibles-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/02/12/Incredibles-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Pixar have made some of my favourite films, from their first feature, the amazing Toy Story, to their incredible take on the superhero genre (if you’ll pardon my pun). Incredibles 2 takes place immediately after the ending of the first film, even though the release was 14 years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We follow the struggles of the Parr family in a world where ‘supers’ are illegal. Elasigirl, or Hellen Parr (the mother) is recruited to act as an example of what a super can be by Rick Dicker and his very &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.autostraddle.com/for-a-movie-thats-not-gay-incredibles-2-sure-is-gay-425276/&quot;&gt;gay&lt;/a&gt; sister Evelyn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animation looked great, as always in Pixar films, and the voice performances were strong. While not my favourite superhero film of 2018 (that would be Black Panther), it’s another strong Pixar film and definitely worth a watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;★★★★☆&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Hamblin-Pyke</name><email>me@humanboring.net</email></author><summary type="html">Pixar have made some of my favourite films, from their first feature, the amazing Toy Story, to their incredible take on the superhero genre (if you’ll pardon my pun). Incredibles 2 takes place immediately after the ending of the first film, even though the release was 14 years later.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FYRE: The Greatest Party That Never Happened (2019)</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/31/Fyre.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FYRE: The Greatest Party That Never Happened (2019)" /><published>2019-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/31/Fyre</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/31/Fyre.html">&lt;p&gt;This film review is my first non-fiction film of 2019, adding a documentary to my list. The short version of my review - it’s great. Definitely worth a watch if you already have Netflix. I don’t have Hulu (it’s not available in the UK) so haven’t watched their &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fyre_Fraud&quot;&gt;similar&lt;/a&gt; documentary released a week beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to go too much into what happens in the documentary, in part because most people know the basic story of the Fyre festival disaster. What I will say is the level of fraud and scam went much farther than I had previously realised, with the whole festival seeming much more like a con than a mistake. What was particularly shocking is the cockiness and arrogance of Billy McFarland. The fact he was still trying to plot new scams while already under investigation was shocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give this film a watch. ★★★★☆&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Hamblin-Pyke</name><email>me@humanboring.net</email></author><summary type="html">This film review is my first non-fiction film of 2019, adding a documentary to my list. The short version of my review - it’s great. Definitely worth a watch if you already have Netflix. I don’t have Hulu (it’s not available in the UK) so haven’t watched their similar documentary released a week beforehand.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Split (2016)</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/22/split.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Split (2016)" /><published>2019-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/22/split</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/22/split.html">&lt;p&gt;This review is pretty late, as my real life responsibilities got in the way a bit. I watched Split as film 2 of 52 this year, and was fairly pleased. The cinematography was great, especially for a horror film. I enjoyed the setting also, with most of the film taking place in an underground complex (the location of which is revealed right at the end so I won’t spoil it). The actors all do a good job in this film, and in particular the two leads (James McAvoy and Anya Taylor-Joy, the latter the star of the excellent 2015 film &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt4263482/&quot;&gt;WITCH&lt;/a&gt;) did an excellent job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should also address the presentation of mental illness in this film. Clearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dissociative_identity_disorder&quot;&gt;DID&lt;/a&gt; (or “split-personality”) in real life is nothing like how it appears in the film. One aspect (personality) cannot be allergic to bees while another is not, and different aspects can’t have differing strengths or abilities. However, I’m willing to overlook many of these issues, as this is clearly meant to be more of a fantastical rather than realistic film. The ending, however, felt like it was trying to be deeper and more meaningful than it actually was, and instead came across as cheesy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I enjoyed watching Split, even if it was kinda dumb at times. ★★★☆☆&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Hamblin-Pyke</name><email>me@humanboring.net</email></author><summary type="html">This review is pretty late, as my real life responsibilities got in the way a bit. I watched Split as film 2 of 52 this year, and was fairly pleased. The cinematography was great, especially for a horror film. I enjoyed the setting also, with most of the film taking place in an underground complex (the location of which is revealed right at the end so I won’t spoil it). The actors all do a good job in this film, and in particular the two leads (James McAvoy and Anya Taylor-Joy, the latter the star of the excellent 2015 film WITCH) did an excellent job.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Greatest Showman (2017)</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/11/the-greatest-showman.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Greatest Showman (2017)" /><published>2019-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/11/the-greatest-showman</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/11/the-greatest-showman.html">&lt;p&gt;Is &lt;em&gt;The Greatest Showman&lt;/em&gt; the best film I’ve ever watched? Unsurprisingly, the answer is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/movie/the-greatest-showman&quot;&gt;no&lt;/a&gt;. It’s cheesy and crowd-pleasing, but at the same time I had fun watching it. The songs were catchy and I can’t fault any of the performances, even if the weren’t Oscar-winning. It’s a perfect popcorn film. Hugh Jackman seems to be moving back to his theatre / musical roots now he’s finished playing Wolverine, and after watching both this and &lt;em&gt;Les Miserables&lt;/em&gt; (and seeing the box-office takings of both) I can totally understand why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;★★★☆☆&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Hamblin-Pyke</name><email>me@humanboring.net</email></author><summary type="html">Is The Greatest Showman the best film I’ve ever watched? Unsurprisingly, the answer is no. It’s cheesy and crowd-pleasing, but at the same time I had fun watching it. The songs were catchy and I can’t fault any of the performances, even if the weren’t Oscar-winning. It’s a perfect popcorn film. Hugh Jackman seems to be moving back to his theatre / musical roots now he’s finished playing Wolverine, and after watching both this and Les Miserables (and seeing the box-office takings of both) I can totally understand why.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Human Boring in 2019</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/10/human-boring-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Human Boring in 2019" /><published>2019-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/10/human-boring-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/01/10/human-boring-2019.html">&lt;p&gt;2018 was a quiet year for me online. I started a PHD program at the University of Manchester, which took up a lot of my time. Additionally, my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/humanboring/&quot;&gt;photo every day&lt;/a&gt; kinda burned out as the year went on. Taking a photo, editing it, and posting it every day was a bit much for me to keep up. Though I mostly managed, there were several missed days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My project for 2019 will be a little different and hopefully a bit easier: I plan to watch a new film every week for the whole year. One important clarification is that by ‘new’ I mean a film that I haven’t already watched, not one that’s been newly released. The second half of this is that I’ll be writing a brief review / my thoughts on the film I watched here. This should mean weekly posts, though some will be delayed (As you might notice, there was no post for the first week of 2019).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be posting my first review later this week, and hopefully my second towards the end of the week or at the start of next.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Hamblin-Pyke</name><email>me@humanboring.net</email></author><summary type="html">2018 was a quiet year for me online. I started a PHD program at the University of Manchester, which took up a lot of my time. Additionally, my photo every day kinda burned out as the year went on. Taking a photo, editing it, and posting it every day was a bit much for me to keep up. Though I mostly managed, there were several missed days.</summary></entry></feed>