<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-12T00:40:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Human Boring</title><subtitle>Thoughts from a boring person</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Incredibles 2 (2018)</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/02/12/Incredibles-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Incredibles 2 (2018)" /><published>2019-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2019/02/12/Incredibles-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2019/02/12/Incredibles-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Pixar have made some of my favourite films, from their first feature, the amazing Toy Story, to their incredible take on the superhero genre (if you’ll pardon my pun). Incredibles 2 takes place immediately after the ending of the first film, even though the release was 14 years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We follow the struggles of the Parr family in a world where ‘supers’ are illegal. Elasigirl, or Hellen Parr (the mother) is recruited to act as an example of what a super can be by Rick Dicker and his very &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.autostraddle.com/for-a-movie-thats-not-gay-incredibles-2-sure-is-gay-425276/&quot;&gt;gay&lt;/a&gt; sister Evelyn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animation looked great, as always in Pixar films, and the voice performances were strong. While not my favourite superhero film of 2018 (that would be Black Panther), it’s another strong Pixar film and definitely worth a watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;★★★★☆&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Pixar have made some of my favourite films, from their first feature, the amazing Toy Story, to their incredible take on the superhero genre (if you’ll pardon my pun). Incredibles 2 takes place immediately after the ending of the first film, even though the release was 14 years later.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Scored - Apple September 2018 predictions</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2018/09/20/apple-predictions-scored.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scored - Apple September 2018 predictions" /><published>2018-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2018/09/20/apple-predictions-scored</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2018/09/20/apple-predictions-scored.html">&lt;p&gt;Apple had their event on 12th September, and I’m finally getting round to grading my predictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iphones&quot;&gt;iPhones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;iPhone X s (5.8”) and X s plus (6.5”) with a new gold colour.&lt;/em&gt; Correct mostly, except the larger XS is called ‘Max’.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;iPhone 9 (6.1” with an X-like design, aluminium frame, a range of colours)&lt;/em&gt; Correct, apart from the name (iPhone XR).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;iPhone 8 and 8 plus.&lt;/em&gt; Correct/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;New replacement for the 7 (possibly using the SE name).&lt;/em&gt; Wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total score: 3/4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-watch&quot;&gt;Apple Watch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;New designs with larger screens but similar x and y dimensions of previous models. Old bands still work. No new colours.&lt;/em&gt; Correct.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;More complications available only on the newer models.&lt;/em&gt; Correct.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Series 3 becomes cheaper, 4g option exclusive to Series 4.&lt;/em&gt; Correct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total score: 3/3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;others&quot;&gt;Others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My prediction for other devices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated Apple TV with faster processor.&lt;/em&gt; Nope.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A release date for AirPower&lt;/em&gt; Wrong. In fact, it may even be &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/linked/2018/09/12/airpower-scrubbed&quot;&gt;cancelled&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A release date for AirPods wireless charging case.&lt;/em&gt; Wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;No new iPads at this event.&lt;/em&gt; Yep.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;No new Macs at this event.&lt;/em&gt; Correct.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;An update on iOS 12 and Mojave (announcing release date, mentioning removal of Group FaceTime).&lt;/em&gt; Not really.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wildcard - Dark Mode exclusive to new iPhones and iPhone X.&lt;/em&gt; No dark mode on iOS this year, so we’ll have to wait for iOS 13.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Score: 2/7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;roundup&quot;&gt;Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall score: 8/14.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year my overall result is 57%, which isn’t the best grade. This is mainly due to having a large number of wildcard picks, with most of them incorrect. I’ll try again when Apple has their next event, most likely next month.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Apple had their event on 12th September, and I’m finally getting round to grading my predictions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple September 2018 event predictions</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2018/09/03/apple-event-2018-predictions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple September 2018 event predictions" /><published>2018-09-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-09-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2018/09/03/apple-event-2018-predictions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2018/09/03/apple-event-2018-predictions.html">&lt;p&gt;In this short post I’ll share my predictions on what Apple will announce in their upcoming September event. I’ll follow-up with another post afterwards grading my own predictions, and seeing if I beat my previous score (2 correct predictions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iPhones
Based on reading various rumours, it seems like a number of new iPhones will be announced next week: A follow up to the iPhone X (maybe called the X s), a larger version of the X, and a 6.1” cheaper iPhone with a similar design to the X. There are also some hints that there might be a replacement to the 7 of some kind. My predictions for the new line-up are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone X s (5.8”) and X s plus (6.5”) with a new gold colour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone 9 (6.1” with an X-like design, aluminium frame, a range of colours)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone 8 and 8 plus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New replacement for the 7 (possibly using the SE name).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple Watch
The Apple Watch series 4 is expected to be announced a this event. Thanks to a leak published by &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2018/08/30/exclusive-apple-watch-series-4/&quot;&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/a&gt; we know they will feature a new design, with the screen taking up more of the face, a tweaked Digital Crown and side button, and a thinner profile. My predictions for the watch are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New designs with larger screens but similar x and y dimensions of previous models. Old bands still work. No new colours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More complications available only on the newer models.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Series 3 becomes cheaper, 4g option exclusive to Series 4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others
My prediction for other devices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated Apple TV with faster processor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A release date for AirPower&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A release date for AirPods wireless charging case.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No new iPads at this event.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No new Macs at this event.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An update on iOS 12 and Mojave (announcing release date, mentioning removal of Group FaceTime).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wildcard - Dark Mode exclusive to new iPhones and iPhone X.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In this short post I’ll share my predictions on what Apple will announce in their upcoming September event. I’ll follow-up with another post afterwards grading my own predictions, and seeing if I beat my previous score (2 correct predictions).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple event scorecard autumn 2017</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2017/10/09/Scorecard-autumn-2017.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple event scorecard autumn 2017" /><published>2017-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2017/10/09/Scorecard-autumn-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2017/10/09/Scorecard-autumn-2017.html">&lt;p&gt;I know this is a little late, but here’s a quick rundown of how I did in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.humanboring.net/2017/09/04/iPhones-in-2017.html&quot;&gt;predictions in September&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-there-will-be-no-7s-&quot;&gt;1. There will be no 7s ✅&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got that right (mostly). The new “normal” iPhones were in fact called the 8 and 8 plus. However, I was wrong about the name of the new, top of the line model. This is infact the iPhone X [^1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-the-edition-will-be-a-taste-from-the-future-&quot;&gt;2. The Edition will be a ‘taste from the future’ ❌&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will have to see about whether the X line continues onto next year, but there was no real justification for this newest, top of the line model above the new design and features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-the-edition-will-be-very-expensive-&quot;&gt;3. The Edition will be very expensive ✅&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The price I predicted was pretty much dead on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;total-score-23&quot;&gt;Total score: 2/3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not bad for a first attempt, though I’ll make a slightly more extensive list of predictions in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^1] Which is pronounced “10” for some strange reason. Nobody will call it that, and they will to have to call the 2019 iPhones something entirely different now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I know this is a little late, but here’s a quick rundown of how I did in my predictions in September.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">iPhones in 2017</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2017/09/04/iPhones-in-2017.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iPhones in 2017" /><published>2017-09-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-09-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2017/09/04/iPhones-in-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2017/09/04/iPhones-in-2017.html">&lt;p&gt;All of the rumours so far have suggested that we’re going to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-08-30/how-apple-plans-to-change-the-way-you-use-the-next-iphone&quot;&gt;three iPhones&lt;/a&gt; announced at the event &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-events/september-2017/&quot;&gt;next week&lt;/a&gt;: two that look somewhat similar to the 7 and 7 plus, as well as another futuristic model. I’ll get a couple of predictions out here so I can say I told you so or face the shame of being wrong online. I’ll be watching the event, and follow up with my score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-there-will-be-no-7s&quot;&gt;1. There will be no 7s&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current rumours are saying that all models will have glass backs, possibly with wireless charging. If the iPhone 7 got a new number, despite looking similar to the 6 in nearly every way, you can bet that models with new materials will get a new number too. My official name predictions: iPhone 8, iPhone 8 plus, iPhone Edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-the-edition-will-be-a-taste-from-the-future&quot;&gt;2. The Edition will be a ‘taste from the future’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third model (Edition), with the front of the device nearly totally covered in screen, will be presented as a way to get the future of the iPhone early. I’m also predicting that this is a one-off event, with the line-up dropping back to 2 models next year. They’ll have very similar designs to this year’s Edition, with a plus-sized model in a similar design available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-the-edition-will-be-very-expensive&quot;&gt;3. The Edition will be very expensive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this model is sitting above the 8 and 8 plus in price (which it will), it’s going to be a very expensive phone. I’m predicting a starting price of $999, though I would expect a large amount of storage included with this. Premium phone, premium price.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">All of the rumours so far have suggested that we’re going to see three iPhones announced at the event next week: two that look somewhat similar to the 7 and 7 plus, as well as another futuristic model. I’ll get a couple of predictions out here so I can say I told you so or face the shame of being wrong online. I’ll be watching the event, and follow up with my score.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Best of 2016 🍾</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2016/12/31/best-of-2016.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best of 2016 🍾" /><published>2016-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2016/12/31/best-of-2016</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2016/12/31/best-of-2016.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s finally the end of 2016, a year that hasn’t been great for many people, me included. In terms of media, however, 2016 has been fairly successful. I’m currently working on “best media of 2016” posts, so keep tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for my personal photo project, I won’t be continuing to post a photo every day, as it has resulted in me sharing below-par pictures on some days. I will still be taking photos every day, and sharing any worthwhile pictures on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/humanboring&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;. I also need to pick a new project for 2017, so I’ll update you when I’ve worked out what that’ll be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-best-photos-of-2016&quot;&gt;My best photos of 2016&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10---dubrovnik-croatia&quot;&gt;10 - Dubrovnik, Croatia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/Dubrovnik.jpeg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to include a picture from my holiday to Croatia, and Dubrovnik was probably the most interesting, and most beautiful, place I visited while there. If you get the chance, spend a few days there, walk around the old town, and visit the nearby beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9---autumn-leaves&quot;&gt;9 - Autumn leaves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/Autumn leaves.jpeg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took this photo the day after my dad’s birthday, right in the middle of autumn as the weather starts to get cold. The evergreen hedge contrasting with the orange and brown leaves from a nearby tree epitomises the season for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8---latitude-festival&quot;&gt;8 - Latitude Festival&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/Latitude.jpeg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latitudefestival.com/&quot;&gt;Latitude&lt;/a&gt; three or four times now, and enjoyed it every time. It’s not to big, meaning you can always get close to the front, and there’s always something else going on if you get sick of the music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7---flowering&quot;&gt;7 - Flowering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/Flowering.jpeg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This picture in May was taken on one of the first really nice days of the year. The blue sky matched the blue/indigo flowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6---tangled&quot;&gt;6 - Tangled&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/Tangled.jpeg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April, spring is usually fully underway. This plant, however, had an unusual split between the green and flowering half and a half of bare branches, showing the tangled mess underneath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5---cape-cod-usa&quot;&gt;5 - Cape Cod, USA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/Cape Cod.jpeg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went with my family to Boston and Cape Cod earlier in the year, visiting my uncle (and having a bit of a holiday). We were extremely lucky with the weather, never having a bad day, so spent most of the time while in Cape Cod on the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4---winter&quot;&gt;4 - Winter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/Winter.jpeg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was taken a few days ago, at around 3pm in Kensington, just as the sun was starting to set. It was a crisp, clear, and very cold day, which is about as good as you can hope for in the middle of winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3---tree-stump&quot;&gt;3 - Tree stump&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/Tree stump.jpeg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tree stump is the remains of a very old tree in Bushy Park that was hit by lightening. All the tiny holes are signs of some sort of life long after the tree itself died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2---fruits&quot;&gt;2 - Fruits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/Fruits.jpeg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was taken with the depth effect on my iPhone 7 plus. I’ve found this mode to be very hit and miss, but when it works you can get a pretty nice effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1---stairs&quot;&gt;1 - Stairs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/Stairs.jpeg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This photo is from one of my favourite places in London, the Tate Modern. Specifically, this picture was taken in its new Switch House extension. The whole of the Tate Modern is an amazing building which has some of the best modern art in the world housed inside. If you ever find yourself in London, make time to visit.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s finally the end of 2016, a year that hasn’t been great for many people, me included. In terms of media, however, 2016 has been fairly successful. I’m currently working on “best media of 2016” posts, so keep tuned.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Best of November 🍂</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2016/12/01/best-of-november.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best of November 🍂" /><published>2016-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2016/12/01/best-of-november</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2016/12/01/best-of-november.html">&lt;p&gt;So its the end of Autumn (or fall if you’re from that part of the world), but it really feels like winter. This morning, as I was walking in to university, it was -3ºC (26ºF), which is the sort below the average for London even in the depths of winter. It being the end of November, we are close to the end of 2016, which if I’m honest I’ll be glad to see the back of, but I’m sure I’ll write about that in next months extra-special End-of-year roundup. Now, onto the photos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BNE70pbjmbX/&quot;&gt;Number 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/IMG_0413.jpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My 5th favourite photo from November, taken from within the grounds of my university as the sun was setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BNW9Ylnjjpd/&quot;&gt;Number 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/IMG_0443.jpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was another photo taken as the sun was starting to set, and you can see the small fluffy clouds reflecting the oranges and pinks of the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BNcHfIjjGiY/&quot;&gt;Number 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/IMG_0452.jpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although a lot of my photos are of nature, plants, on skylines, I really like the sharp geometry found in man-made structures. This could be linked to my love of brutalist architecture as shown in one of my favourite photos of the year (spoilers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BMg7ZcSDlLd/&quot;&gt;Number 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/IMG_0333.jpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This photo, despite being taken at the start of November and featuring autumnal fallen leaves, makes me feel really Xmassy for some reason. Maybe it’s the Spruce-like needles on the hedge in the foreground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BMrLNl5Djkh/&quot;&gt;Number 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/IMG_0351.jpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the only photo using the ‘depth effect’ feature on the iPhone 7 to appear in my round-up this month. That’s in part to do with the hit-and-miss quality of the pictures, and party due to the fact it takes a bit longer to take each picture. Although I’m sure this would look better with a proper DSLR, I’m still pretty pleased with how this photo came out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">So its the end of Autumn (or fall if you’re from that part of the world), but it really feels like winter. This morning, as I was walking in to university, it was -3ºC (26ºF), which is the sort below the average for London even in the depths of winter. It being the end of November, we are close to the end of 2016, which if I’m honest I’ll be glad to see the back of, but I’m sure I’ll write about that in next months extra-special End-of-year roundup. Now, onto the photos:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Best of October 👻</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2016/10/31/best-of-october.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best of October 👻" /><published>2016-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2016/10/31/best-of-october</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2016/10/31/best-of-october.html">&lt;p&gt;On Halloween night, the spoookiest time of the year, I’m writing my round-up of the photos I took over the last month. As always, I’ll list my five favourite photos from October, from fifth to first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-5&quot;&gt;Number 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://instagram.com/p/BL1d5uljDlx/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we’re well into autumn (or fall if you’re American) here in the northern hemisphere, the leaves on the trees are changing into reds and yellows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-4&quot;&gt;Number 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://instagram.com/p/BLl8eXgDCG3/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since getting the iPhone 7+, I’ve been making good use of the 2x lens. This is a good example of where being able to get a closer look at a subject really helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-3&quot;&gt;Number 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://instagram.com/p/BLMOHJmD1VR/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was taken as the sun was starting to set, resulting in some nice long shadows from the rail tracks. Plus it’s always nice to make some use of travel time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-2&quot;&gt;Number 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://instagram.com/p/BMCkVYGDHm1/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a sunset photo looking over the Thames, with some lovely colours reflecting off the water. The wide colour gamut in the new camera (and screen) of the iPhone 7 really makes a huge difference with photos like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-1&quot;&gt;Number 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://instagram.com/p/BLrAsJtjP63/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This photo looks pretty noisy, due to the low light, but I really love the contrast of light and dark. This was taken using the portrait mode feature, which is very hit and miss, but when it works it can make photos look great.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">On Halloween night, the spoookiest time of the year, I’m writing my round-up of the photos I took over the last month. As always, I’ll list my five favourite photos from October, from fifth to first.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Best of September 🍁</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2016/10/01/best-of-september.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best of September 🍁" /><published>2016-10-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2016/10/01/best-of-september</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2016/10/01/best-of-september.html">&lt;p&gt;September has been a busy month for me, first with a visit to Croatia, and towards the end of the month starting a Masters course. Being back in full time education, I will probably not have a huge amount of time to write/tweet, but I will try to share a photo every day still on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://Instagram.com/humanboring&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-5&quot;&gt;Number 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This photo was taken in Richmond at the tail-end of the summer. The river is one of the most relaxing places to be, especially when the sun is shining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-4&quot;&gt;Number 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one of the many photos I took in Croatia, looking over the city of Dubrovnik from the panoramic viewpoint at the top of a nearby mountain. Dubrovnik was one of the most interesting places I visited, aided in part by the fact it is the setting for King’s Landing in Game of Thrones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-3&quot;&gt;Number 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the first photos taken with my new iPhone 7. I’m still experimenting with various features (especially the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/21/hands-on-with-the-iphone-7-plus-crazy-new-portrait-mode/&quot;&gt;portrait mode&lt;/a&gt;), but my early impressions are very positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-2&quot;&gt;Number 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another photo from Croatia, this time taken from the city walls of Dubrovnik’s Old Town. The Adriatic sea is amazingly blue, and since it’s so salty I was actually able to float, something I can never do in a swimming pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-1&quot;&gt;Number 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another photo taken on my iPhone 7 plus. The level of detail, even in these lower-quality Instagram posts, is pretty great. The standout difference, however, definitely has to be the wider colour gamut. These photos really look amazing on the iPhone screen (or I’m sure the smaller iPad pro or a 5K iMac).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">September has been a busy month for me, first with a visit to Croatia, and towards the end of the month starting a Masters course. Being back in full time education, I will probably not have a huge amount of time to write/tweet, but I will try to share a photo every day still on my Instagram</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Woven Nylon band review</title><link href="https://www.humanboring.net/2016/04/08/woven-nylon-band-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Woven Nylon band review" /><published>2016-04-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-04-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.humanboring.net/2016/04/08/woven-nylon-band-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.humanboring.net/2016/04/08/woven-nylon-band-review.html">&lt;p&gt;I bought the new nylon strap for the Apple Watch when it was announced, partly because I &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/03/11/the-apple-watch-nearly-one-year-in.html&quot;&gt;love my watch still&lt;/a&gt;, and partly because it was pretty cheap for a watch band at £39. I’ve been wearing it since it arrived, just over a week ago, so here are my thoughts so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;look&quot;&gt;Look&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose the gold/red colour band, since I already owned the turquoise sport band and wanted something that would look noticeably different. The red and yellow lines make the strap look a warm brown from a distance, which has a nice effect. I particularly like the fact that the inside of the band has the colouring of the Gold/Royal Blue strap. This isn’t something you can see when the watch is on, but it’s a nice little touch. The main thing I dislike is the hard plastic connectors used to slot the strap into the watch — they feel cheap, though what can you expect for the price.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016-04-08-watch1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feel&quot;&gt;Feel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strap is basically comfortable on the wrist, though it isn’t as smooth as the sport band, or as perfectly form-fitting as the Milanese loop. I’d be perfectly happy to wear this strap all of the time if it were the only one I owned, but it’s unlikely to replace my other straps day to day. In terms of how difficult it is to put on, I’d rate it easier than the sport band, but harder than the Milanese. The other thing I have to mention is that the strap has already started to deform slightly in the time I’ve been wearing it. Not a deal-breaker, but something to keep in mind.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016-04-08-watch2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap-up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good strap, which I liked with some caveats. I’d recommend this strap to somebody who owns an Apple Watch with another strap, but if you’re buying a new watch, you’re probably better off getting the sport band to start with. It’s more comfortable, looks very nice, and is more durable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ½ ☆&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I bought the new nylon strap for the Apple Watch when it was announced, partly because I love my watch still, and partly because it was pretty cheap for a watch band at £39. I’ve been wearing it since it arrived, just over a week ago, so here are my thoughts so far.</summary></entry></feed>